amanda.clair.spence



Bilderdijkstraat 66-1, Amsterdam, 1053 KV



+31 652543143



acspence1904@gmail.com

Creative, tenacious, passionate and determined designer of five years, with a keen sense of adveture, always willing to take on new challenges. Having relocated from Africa to Europe and later Australia, has allowed individual to become adaptable when immersed in new environments.

Enjoys learning new skills with focus and confidence.

education

Kingston University **London** (2009-2012) Ba (hons) Fashion Design

Oxford and Cherwell Valley College (2007-2009) BTEC ND Fashion and Clothing

acheivements

Maxmara **Young Designers** 2nd edition **Finalist** invited for interview and Open Day held at MaxMara Head quarters in Reggio Emillia

Winner of Topshop **Accessories Design Competition**Bag design sampled in South America and was later
displayed at Ethical Fashion Week in Paris.

Finalist Old Navy Design Competition

Finalist H and M Design/Print Design Competition

Internation I swimmer represented Swaziland for six cosecutive years at numerous international swimming meets, gaining Victrix Ludorum at the Sub-Saharan International.

skills







Adobe; excellent understanding of all listed programs Microsoft Office; Word, Outlook, Excel, Powerpoint Quest PDM Hand sketching and Illustration

interests

Swimming
Surfing and watersports
Yoga
Painting
Thriftshopping
Arts, crafts and DIY
Interior design
Museums and Exhibitions
Live Music

work experience

freelance designer (m/w) tommy hilfiger- amsterdam 08/07/2018-present

Working with Tommy Hilfiger Sport DesignTeam

- Responsible for design process on specific product categories.
- Technical sketching, hand sketching
- Fully completed Tech Packs
- BOM's
- PLM

swimwear designer (w) hunkemoller- hilversum 20/07/2017-30/07/2018

Lead swimwear designer responsible for full swimwear collections and overseeing the swimwear design team.

- Responsible for seasonal mood, colour and trend research and direction.
- Working alongside buying and merchandiser creating seasonal strategies.
- Creation of full swimwear collections and phasing effectively throughout the season, ensuring the correct balance of products, colours, fabrication and innovation.
- Responsible for full design process from inital design, fabric selection working closely with prototypes through to the final product.
- Working closely with suppliers in Far East in regards to development, sourcing and negotiations.

womenswear and girls designer (m/w) brunotti- amersfoort 01/09/2015-15/07/2017

Working with Senior designer and Head of Design to design two technical and casual sportswear collections a year, with a focus on swimwear in the summer and outerwear in the winter.

- Seasonal mood, colour and trend research and direction.
- Technical sketching, hand sketching
- Responsible for full design process from inital design, working closely with prototypes through to the final product.
- Fully completed Tech Packs
- BOM's
- Artwork and Allover design
- DMU and SMU design

beach performance and lifestyle assistant designer(m/w) o'neill - sydney-10/2014-10/2015

Working alongside Designers and Merchandisers

- Trend , fabric, colour and trim research
- Technical sketching, hand sketching
- Garment specs
- Tech Packs
- BOM's
- Quest PDM
- Print Design

snow and performance outerwear design assistant (m/w) o'neill - amsterdam - 11/2013- 9/2014

Working alongside Senior performance Designers

- Trend , fabric, colour and trim research
- Technical flat sketching, hand sketching
- BOM's
- Quest PDM
- SMU Design
- Tech Packs

freelance design and development (m) byborre - amsterdam - 10/2013 - 01/2014

design assistant (w) ilia visser group-amsterdam-03/2013-10/2013